ANKIT CHOUDHARY

SENIOR MANAGER \$9971316355

• DETAILS •

9971316355 ankitchoudhary2810@gmail.com

• SKILLS •

Project Management

Operations Management

Change Management

Stakeholder Management

Critical Thinking & Problem Solving

Data Analytics

SQL

Customer Retention

Vendor management

Leadership and Teamwork

Communication Skills

• LINKS •

www.linkedin.in/ankitchoudhary28

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

High Skilled Professional with 8+ years of diverse work experience in areas like Inside Sales, Business Analysis, Project Management, NPD and Market Research. Accomplished expertise in growing business revenue from 40L to 3.9cr through effective Strategies, KAM, Problem Solving, Conflict Resolution & Stakeholder Management, leading to a higher customer satisfaction.

TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

The Complete SQL Bootcamp, Udemy

June 2021 — June 2021

Project Management Fundamentals - PMP, Scrum & Agile, Udemy

July 2023 — July 2023

Operations Management A-Z: Business Process and Systems, Udemy

July 2023 — July 2023

Fundamentals of Digital Marketing, Google

July 2021 — July 2021

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Manager - Customer Success at Matrimony.com, New Delhi

September 2021 — Present

- Managed to provide highest revenue of 22cr in last year for inside sales. Quarter wise achievement Q1-5cr, Q2-4cr, Q3-6cr & Q4-7cr.
- Generating revenue in voice process from B2B and B2C clients with the help of 150+ team members of an online marketplace e-commerce.
- Maintaining relationships with key account boosting retention to 75% and reducing churn to 4% through strategic CRM utilization.
- Orchestrated full project lifecycle, utilizing Project Management methodologies like **PMP**, **scrum**, **and agile**, for a successful new product launch.
- Played a pivotal role in creating and delivering compelling product demonstrations, showcasing key features, benefits & prepare RFP's during pre-sales process.
- Drove a 20% revenue surge by conducting meticulous market research and competitor analysis by providing strategic consulting through identifying gaps for internal stakeholders.
- Successfully nurtured relationships with global clients across diverse regions
 including the US, Dubai, and Sri Lanka, ensuring their satisfaction and long-term
 success with our services.
- Supported P&L decisions and maximized ROI through comprehensive CBA for diverse business initiatives.
- Developed and executed customized success strategies for international clients aligning with their specific needs, business objectives, and regional market dynamics for optimal outcomes.
- Excelled in up-selling, cross-selling, and additional training, identifying valuable opportunities.
- Utilized Lean Six Sigma to do root cause analysis(RCA) for swift issue resolution, driving operational excellence and continuous improvement.
- Fostered seamless cross-functional collaboration among Product, Tech, Marketing, and Sales team, enhancing user experience.
- Leveraged Looker Studio, Tableau, and Power BI for data-driven strategies & automation, resulting in a 20% efficiency boost and 15% cost reduction.

 Implemented a robust quality assurance framework, elevating customer satisfaction scores to 4.2

Senior Sales Manager at Shaadisaga, New Delhi

July 2018 — September 2021

- Increased sales revenue from 40L to 3.9 cr for both B2B and B2C clients by effectively understanding consumer needs.
- Problem Solving and Critical Thinking approach through data driven methods using SQL for building overall department strategy.
- Account Management of B2B clients with accountablity from on-boarding to service delivery, also taking care of conflict resolution or escalations if any.
- Successfully negotiated and secured strategic advertising deals, resulting in a 15% increase in revenue from sponsored content and partnerships boosting digital media sales.
- Building and Implementing from scratch in fast paced culture of startup where I designed Benchmarking Operational Matrices for Departmental KPI's and OKR's.
- Led the development and implementation of Service level agreements(SLA's)
 ensuring clear and measurable performance standards for service delivery,
 resulting in improved customer satisfaction and enhanced accountability.
- Developing in-house CRM and adding features with Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment processes for better efficiency.
- Developed and implemented Customer-centric approach resulting in increased customer delight and service levels with average rating of 4.2 in CSAT and 52% of NPS.
- Showcasing Leadership and accountable for **50+** employees to drive revenue growth from multiple departments including executives and managers.

Area Manager at Hindustan Times, New Delhi

April 2017 — July 2018

- Developed and executed revenue growth strategies for their SaaS (Software as a Service) resulting in a 40% increase in annual recurring revenue.
- Spearheaded customer success initiatives, resulting in a 30% increase in customer retention and dropped churn rate to 6%.
- Sales Forecasting and achieving the annual operating plan every year encompassing all decisions of pricing, expansion, batch fill, discounting thus ensuring YOY wise growth rates.
- Effectively utilizing Salesforce features for lead management, opportunity tracking, and sales forecasting.
- Fostered a culture of innovation encouraging team members to contribute ideas that drove product enhancements and operational efficiencies.
- · Preparation and analysis of monthly MIS.
- Creation of SOP's and Training Module, Marketing Activities and School Relationship Management.
- Successfully implemented efficient utilisation of Lead Management System at HTLC.

Assistant Manager at Aditya Birla Fashion and Retail, New Delhi

June 2015 — April 2017

Managed Van Heusen (An apparel brand) at one of the prime locations in New Delhi. Prior to this I was managing Allen Solly where I was handling end to end transactions customer facing, customer support at The Great India Place Mall, Noida which is the one of the biggest and best Allen Solly store in India.

Capitalized the annual revenue of 5.7 crores INR while maintaining the store
efficiency in terms of KPI (Key Performance Indicators)/ Sales Metrics i.e. average
bill value, average basket size.

- Analyzing business through various reports like MBR (Monthly Business Review),
 CBA(Cost Benefit Analysis) and space to sale for Sales Target Management using advanced Microsoft Excel and gave presentation to Top Management using powerpoint.
- Manage end to end store operations which include people management, customer delight, visual merchandise, Product Management, increase profitability and report analysis and action.
- Gave the best ROI's in terms of profitability and service standards consistently for two years.
- Effectively managed and driving growth with a team comprises of 11 sales professionals with help of emotional intelligence and using best practices to get best out of each executive.
- Building relationship with clients through great interpersonal skills and excellent communication skills.

★ AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Above & Beyond

July 2022 — August 2022

Got appreciated for championed the new project management and market research for NPD in 2nd Quarter.

ESOP Grant

February 2021

Appraised for taking revenue from 40L to 3.9cr.

INTERNSHIPS

Financial Advisor at Pnb MetLife, New Delhi

May 2014 — July 2014

As a Financial Advisor helped people with wealth management by introducing them to products of Pnb MetLife.

Website Developer at Aptech Limited

June 2013 — July 2013

Developed SOCIOHUB a social networking website in PHP language.

EDUCATION

B.tech & MBA (Dual Degree), Lovely Professional University, Jalandhar

May 2010 — May 2014

I have completed my B.tech in Computer Science Engineering (2010-2014) and MBA (2013-2015) in Sales and Marketing with 7.0 CGPA overall.

MBA, Lovely Professional University, Jalandhar

May 2013 — May 2015

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

MOODI Festival - IIT BOMBAY

December 2014

Among the top 10 finalist in Modeling Contest.

Nutrionist & Weight Training

October 2020

During lockdown helped many friends and relatives to loose fat and gain strength with proper customized diet solution and training program